You are right, Osman.
You are telling the truth.
You are Turks.
But there are many of us.
Just as we made the Turks kneel in this world...
...we will make you kneel the same way.
Surely, there is a Will that
makes few many and many few.
But you would never learn your lesson from that.
Don't worry.
I will cut your foolish head off.
Alps!
Today is the day to write a legend
with the blood of the infidels. Attack!
Attack Nokers!
Olcaytu Khan's banner.
Hanzade Sargun.
You are right, Ulugan.
It is the magnificent banner of Olcaytu
Khan, whose shadow surpasses the world and...
...whose rule brings peace
to the world that stops you.
Osman Bey!
Let not that sword be
pointed in the wrong direction.
He who always points his sword in the wrong
direction will ride his horse into wrong ways.
But don't worry.
We always draw our swords against you.
Now, my words are for everyone in this square.
By the command of Esenbike
daughter of Olcaytu Khan...
...this battle has ended before it began.
Today, in this square it is Esenbike alone..
...who will decide who
shall live and who shall die.
Esenbike huh?
Esenbike, right.
You have no way out of this forest, Osman.
You will tell me, you demon!
You will tell me!
Aunt...
Where is my daughter? You will...
..tell me!
Never!
You will never learn where she is, Bala! Never!
I will! Get up
God, what am I going to do?
Get up!
I will learn Sofia.
Esenbike..
We would welcome you if you told us
you were going to come to the frontiers.
Osman!
Kneel.
The one whose eyes you
stare into is not your equal.
Wait..
Wait...
What will you do?
Will you make us kneel?
Huh?
The fate of those who tried
to make us kneel is clear.
So Ulugan...
Come on now.
If you have power show me.
Nokers!
Sargun!
Why did you stop your son? Let him...
I should let him so...
...he can do what you
couldn't do until this day, right?
My order is definite!
This battle is over for now!
Esenbike or whatever your name is...
You came to the frontiers.
While you can unite with Ulugan...
...and attack us...
...you want to make an agreement with us, huh?
Tell me. What is the
reason of your arrival here?
It is first arresting our
short-sighted Commander Ulugan.
What are you going to do Altuga?
Will you draw your sword?
I would never my Hanzade.
What are you doing, Esenbike?
You did not follow Olcaytu Khan's orders.
You disgraced his name on the frontiers.
Our Khan will punish you.
Take him away. -Chain him!
Well, Ulugan, well...
I am the strongest Commander
of glorious Mongol state!
You cannot touch me! Don't you dare!
Ulugan!
And you, Osman Bey...
With my father Olcaytu Khan's order...
...I want to talk to you and
make an agreement with you.
If that's what you are saying...
..let's talk then.
Esebike..
Hatun.
Not now.
We will have iftar together
at Sahinkaya together.
You will listen to me there.
Nokers!
Take him!
Esenbike, you're making a
huge mistake. I'm telling you.
Osman!
You're responsible for this situation!
I will make you pay for this!
I swear I will!
Boran. Cerkutay.
My Bey.
Follow that woman.
Watch where she goes and inform me.
As you order my Bey.
Now...
Now we will see...
...what that woman is
doing and what her game is.
We will reveal it.
And we'll know her purpose
Esenbike, huh? Esenbike.
You have to speak!
Sofia.
If you care about your life
...tell me where my sister is.
Otherwise, you're going to die here.
What do you think will happen
when I tell you where Halime is?
Who are you? Alaaddin.
What are you to Halime? Nothing!
She's not your sister but your enemy only.
Give me patience, my Allah.
You did something evil.
But when we and my sister come together.
...everything will be as before.
Don't worry.
Just a dream.
Just a dream. That will never happen.
Bala!
Halime will never come back to you.
She's my girl.
She's my girl!
My daughter!
You can't call my daughter your girl, Sofia!
I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
If you call her your girl
again, I won't mind anything!
-Mom, stop. She may die!
-I'll kill you, Sofia!
-Mother!
-I'll kill you!
-I will kill you!
-Mother, stop!
-She says she's her girl!
-Mom, stop.
If she dies, we will never know where Halime is.
Just stop.
Look what that hatun did, brothers.
She chained Ulugan without hesitation.
Whatever goes around
comes around, brother Samil.
The one who tried to take my Bey to his Khan...
...is now going through the same thing.
Right.
If Ulugan is chained
because he couldn't beat us...
Olcaytu's daughter.
Why would she come to our
land and make peace with us?
I can predict her purpose.
She isn't like Ulugan.
A woman..
..is never like a man.
They never know what they can do, son.
So we need to be careful.
When Boran and Cerkutay
are back, we will discuss this.
Let's have a talk with Esenbike.
-We'll know what her purpose is.
-Okay, my Bey.
I'm the high commander of
the glorious Mongolian State!
Stop this disgrace! Now!
Otherwise, I will ignore the laws...
...and break these chains here!
Then nobody can stand against me.
I am...
...Great Olcaytu Khan's daughter!
The reputation of our state
got ruined because of you!
You will be punished, Ulugan!
If you unchain yourself now,
...Osman will put the chain
around your neck after me.
For your information.
What are you talking about?
Osman's alps are following
us. If I release you now.
...my game will end before it even starts.
So keep crying out.
You'll know everything when we go to the tribe.
If you don't silence the prisoner.
...I will silence you nokers!
Come on!
We're going to the tribe!
Get off! Alright!
I can walk myself!
Look at that. You see that hatun, brother?
She's making Ulugan come after her like a dog.
I know her well, brother.
She can bury even a thousand
Ulugans, not a single one.
That's obvious.
Even you seem scared.
Brother, her arrival won't
be good for any of us.
Let's follow them, brother.
Meryem, bring water!
-Calm down!
-Alaaddin, leave it!
She says she's her girl!
Meryem, make her drink.
If this demon dies, we'll
never know where my sister is.
-Mother. Leave me
Leave me.
Leave me!
Leave me! Leave me!
No mercy! Don't show mercy for her!
She doesn't deserve it! She doesn't deserve!
You're going to die soon, Sofia!
I'll make you pay for all the sufferings
you made my daughter go through.
I will make you pay for them one by one!
-Mother, she may die.
-I'm going to make you pay, Sofia!
Make you pay! I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
You don't know how much she suffered, heartless!
Bala!
I never made her suffer.
If she had stayed with us,
she would have suffered.
She doesn't even remember you.
We'll see that when it's time, Sofia.
But you won't be able to see!
I'll bring my daughter back
but you won't be able to see that.
Because you're going to die!
You're going to die.
-You're going to die.
-Alright.
I'm not going to die here, Bala.
I'm not going to die!
I'm stronger than you think!
Stronger!
I have many friends who
will never leave me here, Bala.
Don't trust anyone, Sofia.
Neither Ulugan nor the emperor.
If you don't speak, nobody can take you from me.
Nobody.
Mother. Mother...
She's just under your nose.
But you'll never be able to find her.
Mother, mother.
-She won't speak, mother.
-She will.
One way or another, she will.
She'll either speak or die.
Mother, Sofia is smart.
She knows we won't kill her
before we learn where Halime is.
Mother, death can't scare her.
-It'll be very hard to make her speak.
-She will speak!
First, we'll kill her hopes. She'll see
she can never get out of here alive.
Alaaddin, put her in the cage tent.
Arrange some guards. Tell
them to keep a sharp lookout.
As you order, mother.
But...
Seeing Sofia is missing they will come for her.
-We have to make her speak fast.
-We need to hurry up then.
No bread! No water!
When she passes out,
they'll wake her up with water.
Wash her in the cold water!
She's forbidden to sleep!
She'll speak. Drown her
in the water. Wake her up.
Meryem.
Why are you so upset?
I am...
I was thinking what she did to you.
Bala Hatun, what can I do?
-If there's anything...
You already helped, my girl.
By finding the bottle, you got Sofia caught.
Thank you
Thank you.
Come on, come on.
Who is the one coming, Ilbay?
Enlightened in the front.
Dark in the back.
Olcaytu's daughter.
Esenbike.
Take Ulugan to the caged tent.
What are you looking at like that?
Kneel
Greet the daughter and
grandson of glorious Olcaytu Khan.
We are Turks. We do not kneel before anyone.
Then..
..I will take your life.
All of you, either kneel or die.
All Turks will one day...
...be buried in the carcass pit you deserve.
I am Ilbay Bey, the Bey of the Kayi tribe.
We did not know you would come, Esenbike Hatun.
Was I supposed to inform you, Ilbay?
I enter wherever I want, whenever I want.
Why did you arrest Ulugan, Esenbike Hatun?
You have become the Bey's Hatun...
...but you couldn't learn that every
word should not be spoken everywhere.
Come with me to my tent.
I guess you did not hear my mother.
Come on! Walk!
These dogs are all the same.
They show their power with
swords against the innocent...
and then ask for peace
Sargun's eyes looked like a wild tiger.
Esenbike's desire for peace holds him back.
A tiger, huh? A tiger.
When he is allowed and
attacks, I will thrust that sword
soaked in the blood of
the innocent, into his throat.
Then they will get out of our tribe!
They put Ulugan in the caged tent as well.
So, the woman kept her word, brother.
Now she will sit on the throne.
And that is what I fear.
Why do you fear? Will
they let her take the throne?
Brother...
Ulugan is the shadow...
...this Hatun is the sun. She
burns anyone who gets close.
Now everything will be much harder.
Come on.
-Bala.
My Bey.
Bala... Are you alright?
-We are alright.
We are alright. Alaeddin.
Welcome, my Bey.
-Thank you. What is the situation? Tell me.
My daughter...
We captured the demon Sofia,
my Bey. She is in the caged tent.
But no matter what I did, I
could not make her speak.
We will question her. We will.
Thanks to Allah, you have brought the
Turkmen Alps safely across the border.
Welcome, Ayaz Bey. You have strengthened
us in our difficult day. Thank you.
May the Turks live, Bala Hatun. In
this path, we are ready to die, for sure.
-What about the other Beys? Where are they?
-They turned out to be cowards who ran away.
I wish I could see Ulugan's
face when the Turkmen
Alps got rid of their
disguises of nokers, my Bey.
Today, in that square, we
were about to take his life, but...
But?
Esenbike Hatun and her son Sargun
came with their army and stopped us.
Who is this Esenbike Hatun?
Esenbike is the daughter of the
Mongol Khan Olcaytu Khan, Holofira.
Now that she has arrived
in the frontiers, it will
be more difficult to take
our tribe back, father.
Zolzaya.
Remove these ugly covers.
-Put the ones from Tabriz instead.
-Right away, ma'am.
From now on, on the frontiers...
...not a single stone will
move without my permission.
Those who do not obey my order
will be treated as lower than dogs.
Let Ulugan's fate..
...be a lesson to you.
Now first..
...I will finish the war that Ulugan started.
I will make peace with Osman.
Esenbike...
As the leader of Kayi, I
am always at your service.
As if the opposite was possible, huh? Ilbay...
Forgive my courage, but you
have the power to kill Osman.
If you ask me, let's not make
peace with Osman and take his head.
I do not ask.
I do not ask anyone, I only command.
And I take the head of those
who do not obey my order.
It is not our right to question, of course.
We just know Osman.
Hatun
If you do not close your mouth soon,
this acquaintance will take you to death.
After all that happened,
Osman will not agree to peace.
He will have conditions.
There is no condition that
my power cannot crush.
Osman will have to make peace.
I will leave him no other choice.
You have come the end of the way.
I still have a long way to go, Osman.
This is just the beginning for me.
The end of your way goes through my sword.
You will tell me where Halime is.
And I will kill you right away.
Osman, what do I gain in return
when I tell you where Halime is?
Will you allow me to live?
Me, the one who made you
and your family suffer for years...
...the one who hid your
daughter from you for ten years...
Will you release me?
Look at me.
You know me well.
I don't tell lies.
You will tell me where Halime is.
And I will kill you.
Then forget about your daughter.
Osman, I will never tell you where she is.
Then you will rot here.
While I rot here you will never...
...reunite with your baby gazelle.
You will tell me where
Halime is, or I'll kill you!
We will make a deal, Osman.
We will make a deal.
If you set me free...
...I will give your daughter back to you.
Or else..
...you will never be able to find her.
We won't make a deal.
You will die!
Osman. Osman, stop.
Osman, stop!
Don't.. Please, don't! She is the
only one who knows where Halime is!
-Bala.
-Osman.
Let's not lose our daughter once again.
-Bala... -She will speak!
She will speak. I promise, she will. Don't.
Let's not lose her, please.
It's your decision.
You have the chance to convince Osman.
If you set me free
...your ten years of pain
for your child will end.
Osman.
-Bala...
My Osman.
To reunite with my Halime,
with our daughter, I am
holding on to even the smallest
hope and chasing after it.
Osman.
My Bey! My Bey!
-Peace be upon you
-Peace be upon you, my Bey.
Peace be upon you too, tell me.
Did that Hatun loosen Ulugan's chains?
Ulugan did everything he could
to save himself, my Bey, but...
...they did not give him a chance for a moment.
My Bey, they dragged him like a dog
with chains and threw him into the tent.
His nokers could not even look at
him out of respect for Esenbike Hatun.
It seems the snake is changing its skin, huh?
What will happen now, my Bey?
We will accept that Hatun's invitation.
Then we will understand her intentions.
Get out
This plan you made...
It better be worth disgracing me, Esenbike.
Don't talk as if you don't know me, Ulugan.
Once I get my teeth into something,
I do not let go without tearing it apart.
Don't worry.
When I am done with Osman, you
will be the only ruler of the frontiers.
What is this great plan?
What is this game, this plan for?
I will make an agreement with Osman.
Tonight, I will present my conditions to him.
Agreement for what?
Osman will either pay taxes...
...or let his daughter Fatma marry my son.
Either way, we will win.
Don't even try...
Osman will never accept this.
Then open your ears and
listen to me carefully, Ulugan.
Osman has no other choice.
You have struck the blow.
But I will be the one to tear his heart out.
He will have to kneel.
How will you succeed?
Not just me...
...we will do it together.
While I am meeting with Osman...
...you will escape from here.
What is this game for?
Esenbike... She has great power.
She does.
Nobody in the frontiers can compete with her.
But I'm not afraid of her power...
...but that she wants to make peace with Osman.
We should find out her purpose first.
No.
Whatever her purpose is.
...she'll throw us under Osman's
feet without hesitation to make peace.
-Didn't you see her? -Osman won't kneel.
And he won't make peace, Ilbay.
It's better if he does. But I
won't let that happen, Begum.
Never.
Come on, hurry up! Prepare
the table immediately!
My father Olcaytu Khan wanted
Osman's head under his feet.
But you convinced him about this game, mother.
So... What do you think we should do now?
If he comes here and turns down our offer.
...we should drink Osman's
blood instead of water in this table.
You're so immature, Sargun.
You don't see for what purpose I'm doing this.
Today or tomorrow.
...Osman will have to accept our offer.
Esenbike Hatun.
Osman Bey is here.
Destroying Osman who
damaged Mongolians so much...
...would only make him a hero.
We'll wipe him out of
the world with the politics.
Esenbike Hatun.
I knew you wouldn't turn
down my invitation, Osman Bey.
Welcome.
We aren't here to eat.
We're here to hear you.
We will talk. We will talk.
Time is coming.
Let's break fast first.
My Allah.
I'm before You with the prayer of Hadhrat Jacob.
You helped him and Joseph come back together.
So help me and my daughter come back together.
You are the One Who
accepts the prayers, my Allah.
Please fulfill our longings and
make our ways join together.
Aameen.
-Aameen.
May Allah accept.
In the name of Allah,
the merciful, the compassionate.
Thanks, mother.
Thank you, mother.
Here.
-In the name of Allah.
-Bala Hatun.
You need to break your fast. You need energy.
Thank you, my girl.
In the name of Allah, the merciful,
the compassionate.
Are you thinking about Sofia?
No.
Thinking about my Halime.
Sofia raised her like a Christian.
But I don't get it.
How can she not remember us?
She forgot her mother, father,
brothers and even her real name.
Mother.
She was too young when she was abducted.
Who knows what Sofia did to her?
She's cruel enough to take
away a little child from her family.
She can do anything.
Maybe, she didn't forget.
Maybe, Sofia is saying so to hurt you.
Besides, even if a child forget everything.
...she can never forget the
affection that her parents gave her.
Gonca is right, mother.
Good memories can never be forgotten.
You'll see. When Halime is back,
everything will be better than before.
-God willing.
Especially her first fast.
She was just a little kid.
But she insisted on fasting. Remember, Bala?
Yes. How can I even forget?
She almost passed out due to hunger.
And her father could hardly convince her.
She broke her fast in the afternoon azan.
Meryem.
Do you remember your first fast?
No.
I don't remember.
It means you were too young...
...when you first fasted, my girl.
What if Sofia doesn't speak?
She will.
Her collaborator Ulugan who
could save her is gone now.
She'll lose her hopes.
She has to speak.
Well... You invited us to the iftar.
So we shared your food.
You say come to the point now.
Esenbike Hatun, you took Ulugan from me.
And you said you wanted to make peace.
Tell me. What is your purpose
of coming to the frontiers?
My purpose is nothing more
than you heard, Osman Bey.
I came to end the war
that Ulugan and you started.
Whose soldier is Ulugan?
Why did he come to the frontiers?
He wanted to make me kneel
as Olcaytu Khan's soldier.
In these lands,
...there is peace if you want peace...
...and there is war if you want war.
But you should know this.
No annexation.
You have to stop there.
This is the part where you are wrong, Osman Bey.
You don't look into the matter.
You just see the names and titles.
We promise you a range that you can't even see.
What's the thing I can't see?
Open my eyes then, Esenbike Hatun.
You Turks..
If you take the right side,
...you won't be a threat against
but a gain in the west for...
...the Ilkhanid State that
is flourishing in the east.
So...
You tell me to fight Byzantine...
...while Mongolians are
fighting in the east, right?
I'm talking about alliance.
But you call it annexation.
What does it matter, Osman Bey?
You'll find peace under the
shadow of the victorious one.
This alliance can make
the whole world one state.
Just think about the consequence.
But this gift will have a price.
Tell me now.
How can we even find peace
under the shadow of Mongolians?
You're a smart man, Osman Bey.
But let me explain.
You have to pay taxes like the
other states under our authority.
My answer to this question...
...is known by everyone.
I told Ulugan. Now I'll tell you.
Not a single coin from my
treasure or my people's pouches...
...is going to Mongolians.
I know. I know.
I know you can't pay the tax...
...even if you accept our offer.
For this reason, I have another offer for you.
I've heard...
...that you have a beautiful
daughter called Fatma.
-Father!
-What is she saying, my Bey?
Wait.
This won't make us enemies...
...but relatives, Osman Bey.
If you make your daughter
Fatma marry my son Sargun
...you'll be subject to the
Ilkhanid State without taxes...
...and be our most powerful
commander in the west.
Well..
You invited us to your table.
Thank you.
I always have respect for the host.
But what you said will never happen.
I won't let that happen.
My word is final!
You have to pay the tax!
You have two days.
Osman Bey Secret Tents
Bala Hatun's orders. Nobody can go in.
I've brought bread and water.
She shouldn't die of hunger.
She should die but...
...she has to live to speak.
You're right. Go. But come out quickly.
Poena.
-What ate you doing here?
-Aunt.
Aunt.
I've brought bread and water for you.
Don't worry. I'll get you out of here.
-No, no.
I can't put you in danger.
Just send a message to
Hristo. Tell him where I am.
He and Ulugan will burn down this place.
That's not possible.
A woman called Esenbike has come.
-Esenbike?
They said she chained Ulugan.
Olcaytu's daughter.
Damn it. What is she doing here?
I'll try to send a message to Hristo.
But if Bala finds out that
you lied about Halime,
...they will kill you.
My little bird.
I opened such a wound inside them...
Hey, look at me.
They can't do anything to me.
Aunt.
Halime is really dead.
Isn't she?
Of course. I'm just using my enemy's weakness.
Why did you ask?
You're saying such words...
...that it's like real.
Even I believe you.
I'm a good liar, my little bird.
Are you taking your medicine?
Do you care about me even in such a situation?
Poena, you are very precious to me.
Very precious.
Don't forget to take your medicine.
Don't worry. I'm taking it.
Beat her well. She has to speak.
As you order, Bala Hatun. One
way or another, I'll make her speak.
I'm glad I have you, aunt.
I will do my best to save you from here.
Don't be sad.
This doesn't suit you at all.
Poena, both you and I are very strong.
And I'll get out of here.
You little fool!
You little demon!
-You think I will speak to you?
-What's going on?
What are you doing here, Meryem?
-I am...
I wanted to make her speak.
I wanted to end your suffering.
-How did you get in here?
-Sisters were bringing bread and water.
I said I'd take them.
Bala.
Did you send your tail to me
thinking she can convince me?
I won't speak, Bala.
Convince Osman to promise
that he will release me.
Kismet! Nobody but you will go in here!
You get out. We will talk.
Are you hungry, Sofia?
I know you don't want to die.
A last chance for you.
If you speak now, you can sleep
comfortably one last time tonight.
-If you don't speak, it's your choice.
-Bala.
Will you torture me with hunger?
I come from hell.
And in front of you, this
is not Sofia that you know.
You try to..
...make me give up..
...but we will see who gives up.
We'll see Sofia.
We'll see.
-No...
We'll see!
No!
Remember, Osman Bey.
You have two days. No more.
You will either pay the tax or give
your daughter as a bride to our family.
Think about what I said. Come
to me with a positive answer.
Or else..
Or what?
Esenbike Hatun.
Or the light of this world will go out for Kayi.
So many lives will be lost.
These lands will be ruined.
Even if we are ruined...
...even if we die on this path...
...we will never give up.
Don't...
...worry about it.
Esenbike Hatun.
Rebel Ulugan escaped from
Kayi tribe, Esenbike Hatun.
What?
Ulugan escaped, huh?
You couldn't even keep
a dog in a cage. Get lost!
Sargun.
Go after them immediately.
Bring and throw him at my feet.
Even though Olcaytu Khan wanted you alive,
what you did brought your death, Ulugan.
You should also be careful, Osman Bey.
Ulugan will first attack you.
He will want to prevent the peace we made.
We'll see.
Esenbike's arrival is not good, Ulugan.
But she has planned her game well.
A wolf...
...cannot be deceived by games.
Osman will neither give
his daughter nor pay the tax.
Esenbike..
...left the palace.
But this is the Anatolian plain.
Here, we walk over the heads
that are cut off from their bodies.
Esenbike will learn this as well.
Does Osman have a choice to make a move, Ulugan?
Esenbike can destroy him with just one order.
Not just Esenbike...
...even if Olcaytu Khan comes from Tabriz
no one can take Osman from my hands.
I will take his life.
Ulugan.
Your path is my path.
I will do as you say even if I
have to put my life at risk. But...
...will we stand against Esenbike?
I see the one standing against me as
someone who has given up on their life.
Altuga.
But..
For now..
...we will do as she says.
Get ready.
Now...
...it is time...
...to drip blood from the swords.
What are you saying, my Bey? That woman
lost her mind. That will never happen.
My Fatma... No!
My father told Esenbike the
same thing, mother. He said no.
But that woman doesn't care, mother.
She says "Either you will pay the tax, or...
...I will take Fatma as a bride to my family."
Father...
Fatma.
What is my brother saying, father?
Does Esenbike want me as a bride?
Don't worry, my daughter, don't worry.
We have given the necessary answer.
Even if you say no, what
if they take me by force?
How can such a thing happen?
Huh?
Would I ever leave the
light of my eyes like that?
No, don't worry.
You won't leave me.
You won't, right...
If this woman is as strong as you say, Gonca...
...when the time she gave us is up...
When the time is up, we will
give the necessary answer.
Children, inform the Beys.
Let's discuss this matter in the council.
-As you order my Bey.
Let alone ruling a tribe...
...you cannot even herd sheep.
I entrusted my prisoner to you in your tribe.
You couldn't keep him there.
And without looking at your weakness...
...you consider Osman your enemy.
Esenbike Hatun...
...there are more Nokers
than Alps in this tribe.
If you are looking for someone
guilty, look at your own soldiers.
Ilbay Bey is right.
Apparently, Altuga helped him.
Otherwise, he couldn't have escaped.
Our Alps do not betray us.
They do not let criminals escape.
Look for the traitors among yourselves.
This situation of yours brings tears to my eyes.
You support each other.
Good.
I care about the result.
But I don't see Ulugan in the tribe.
What is the result of the meeting then?
Did Osman accept your conditions?
He will. He will either accept...
...or he will die.
I gave Osman two days.
He will both pay me taxes and...
...give me his daughter.
Osman Bey Secret Tents
The fire inside me would
even heat the cold of this night.
It is like I've been thrown into a blind well.
This is the well of lovers, Yusuf.
Those who are burnt to ashes and those who
can resist separation comes out of this well.
In the name of Allah. Fatma Hatun.
Are you alright?
How can I be alright, Yusuf Bey?
The Mongols have asked for me from my father.
You must have heard about it, right? -I have.
I have, I know.
But it would be impossible to...
...take a precious Hatun like you, I
mean the daughter of Osman Bey...
...that's what I thought.
My father won't give me to them.
But what if...
-No.
No, Fatma Hatun, there is no
such possibility. It's impossible.
They will have to step over
my dead body to take you.
I mean...
...no one.
...would want a girl who even makes
the sun jealous, a brave Turkish girl...
...to rot in the hands of those Mongol dastards.
I mean... that's what I think.
Thank you, Yusuf Bey.
But I'm afraid of their armies
coming here and attacking us.
Meryem.
Why are they here? -Meryem...
Where are you going?
I couldn't sleep.
I thought I'd take some fresh air until suhoor.
Meryem, it's very cold. You'll
catch a cold, you'll get sick.
It's obvious I won't sleep tonight either.
You'll be my companion. We'll talk, huh?
Is there an army stronger
than your eyes, Fatma Hatun?
Apparently, I won't sleep tonight either.
God..
Let us raise our child in health.
Give us a good life to spend with him.
Protect Orhan and our child from all evil.
Amen.
Holofira.
My beautiful one...
My beautiful wife...
Why didn't you go to sleep?
When have I ever slept without
your presence here, Shahzade Orhan?
My wife, my spring flower.
I know you won't sleep.
But Holofira, you're carrying two lives now.
You need to be careful
about eating and sleeping.
-Look, my mother... She warned me.
-How does she do it?
Being a mother to us all...
Worrying for all of us... Loving all of us...
I'm already afraid something
might happen to our baby.
When I think that my mother
feels the same fear for all of us...
Orhan.
Do you think...
...I will be a good mother?
Sure you will.
Sure you will. Lord's daughter.
Are you sure?
-I am sure.
Come here, come. Come.
My Holofira
Did..
What did pregnancy do to me?
I don't know. You
are just a little...
A little what?
I cannot say it but.. -Orhan! -Holofira...
Look. Your hand is heavier now.
My hand got heavier.
I got heavier too, didn't I, Orhan Bey?
My beautiful wife, my spring flower.
Did I say that? I say pregnancy
added beauty to my wife's beauty.
But you don't believe me, right?
Then take this. Look at it.
This is a lotus (Nilufer).
Orhan, this is beautiful.
-It's beautiful.
But...
it's not as beautiful as you.
Go to sleep now, alright?
I'll perform my ablution and
read the Qur'an until suhoor.
But you were going to read the Al-Kahf to me.
And you were going to explain what it means.
Don't think I forgot.
You just don't want to go to sleep...
-I would never.
Do I need to perform ablution to listen?
You don't need to, my Hatun.
Come here.
My beautiful Hatun.
-Did she speak?
-She won't speak.
I want that snake to be
punished more than you, Osman.
But what about Halime?
Our daughter?
Who knows what she's doing right now?
The Mongols are right here.
Our people are in a miserable situation.
The fate of our daughter is in
the hands of that poisonous snake.
If we keep Sofia alive, there's
hope to reunite with our daughter.
But what if she doesn't speak?
What if she continues her game?
Are we going to be her prisoners then?
My Bala, don't.
Don't, my gazelle-eyed
one. Don't shed your tears.
Look, my Halime is alive. You
see. We'll find her. We'll take her.
We'll take her and the tribe.
Don't cry, don't shed these beautiful tears.
We got over many hardships until now.
We will get over this too. Don't worry.
We'll find her, Osman. We
will win this battle, God willing.
Did I ever lose something
when I had you by my side?
You'll see, all ways will open before us.
When I close my eyes, her face comes before me.
She's crying out for her mother.
Who knows what that demon did to our daughter?
-What did our daughter suffer?
-Hush.
No, no.
We'll think about the good days...
...not the days we lost.
Alright?
What if she doesn't
remember us when we find her?
Even if our daughter doesn't remember her mother
...her mother raised her right here.
-Here.
-Yes.
You saved me from my burden again, my Osman.
Without you, what could I count on?
I'm your protector. You are my companion.
I'll fight any battles with you.
You say we'll end this battle happily?
We will win this battle too.
Again?
I told you to wait in the tent.
-Father, well...
-You may catch cold, Aykiz.
Take her to the tent.
We're under attack!
-Father.
-Stay in the tent.
Leave no heads over the shoulders! Attack!
Get your bloody hands off my tribe, dog!
I burned down the tribes all night.
Now you're going to burn with your tribe.
Burn down!
Burn down their tents and tribe!
We've been burning the tribes
who pledged loyalty to Osman.
They'll wake up into a nightmare.
I'll make them wish they were dead, Altuga!
Osman Bey Secret Tents
They all know we won't kneel.
So she set a condition to make us kneel.
Although Ayaz Bey and his alps joined us,
...we still can't drive Esenbike
out of the frontiers, my Bey.
Orhan Bey is right.
To become more powerful
for more alps and swords.
...we need money.
Well..
The enemies know that they can
put us in a tight spot with money.
But we have to find the money
to stand against Mongolians.
Well... My Bey.
It's not just little money. How can we find it?
With the money of Mongolians.
Don't worry, son.
We'll hit Mongolians with
the money of Mongolians.
Do I have permission, my Bey?
Come in, Aykurt.
My Bey
The dog called Ulugan
raided all the Turkmen tribes.
He slaughtered people, my Bey.
What are you saying, Aykurt Cavus?
She said nothing, Bala Hatun.
Sofia.
I never give up, Bala.
For years, I waited for vengeance.
And you think I will give up so easily?
If not today, you will give up tomorrow.
Beat her hard, Kismet.
You'll speak. I can wait, Sofia.
But Halime can't wait, Bala.
She doesn't have much time.
What do you mean?
Bala.
You have to release me.
For Halime.
Sofia!
Game is over, Sofia.
Whatever you say, you won't get out of here.
Look, Bala.
If you don't let me go,
Halime will die tomorrow.
What?
My soldiers must have
realized my absence, Bala.
"Three days if Osman
catches me", I said to them.
If I don't go back in three days,
...they will kill Halime.
Whatever you say! I'm sick of your lies!
-I'm sick of you!
-It's real.
I'm telling the truth.
I swear to God that it's the truth, Bala.
If you don't want her to be killed.
...you have to release me.
Otherwise, she'll die tomorrow.
You'll cause your daughter to die.
Just let me go.
We don't have much time, Bala.
Ulugan, Ulugan.
You rabid dog attacking around.
As soon as he ran away from Esenbike
...he attacked innocent Turks.
It's us who caused him to lose
favor with Olcaytu, Alaaddin Bey.
Ulugan's grudge and hatred...
...is against us more than our people.
Maybe, it's not about only his
hatred against us, my Shahzade.
You're right, brother.
My Bey.
We heard Esenbike.
What if Ulugan is trying to
prevent the peace as she said?
Even if find the gold now, my Bey
...we can't fight both Ulugan and
Esenbike in two fronts at the same time.
My Bey, I know what they call peace
requires us to kneel and pay taxes.
But...
-No.
With Ulugan's new move
...things have changed.
Beys, there is nothing to do.
We will pay the tax to Mongolians.
The Mongolian gold that we were going to use
to drive Esenbike out of the frontiers...
We'll pay it to Mongolians as the tax.
I'm standing by my word.
Not a single coin from the treasure of
my people's pouches will go to them.
Esenbike will think that
we made peace and knelt.
In fact, we will buy time to choke them.
How will we get the Mongolian gold, my Bey.
-Well...
Here is the answer of that question.
Samil, Balaban, Kanyumaz.
They've been watching
Ulugan's nokers. Speak now.
As you order, my Bey.
As Osman Bey said, we've been
watching their every step for some time.
Before Esenbike came to the frontiers
...carts loaded with gold would come
to Ulugan from the nearby beylics.
What's the load?
The taxes collected beyond the
eastern border of Kayi, Ulugan.
Altuga, put these beside the others. Come on.
Thinking where they could
keep the gold, we followed them.
Come on, carry the chests.
Hide them well in the cave.
They dropped the chest in front of our eyes.
What are you doing?
All the gold coins fell on the ground.
Allah knows how much more
they are keeping in that cave.
My Bey, that's why they're
providing tight security.
Kanyumaz, what you saying is...
My Bey.
Your plan is taking Ulugan's gold...
...and giving it to Esenbike as the tax, huh?
This will be enough to buy time
until we regain our strength, my Bey.
Esenbike..
...will think I have to accept the peace.
But we'll regain strength.
First, we will kill Ulugan and then...
...and then stop Esenbike.
Here we go.
Let's pay a visit to that cave.
My mother Sultan.
Shah of Shahs.
You didn't think anyone
was worthy of your precious.
But you prepared so much
for a shepherd's daughter.
It means there is a great benefit for us.
This is a great chance for you to
prove that you're a grandchild worthy...
...of Olcaytu Khan, my boy.
My Sultan, Ulugan carried out your orders.
He raided all the nearby
tribes and slaughtered people.
He seized their everything.
Good. Good.
Now..
...you're trapped, Osman.
Still, he will look around
for the tax you ordered.
He'll come back with empty
hands from everywhere.
We have all the treasures...
...of the tribes, Sogut and all the castles.
But Osman will try something.
He will attempt to take back...
..what we took from him.
He'll come for the Mongolian
treasure that we're keeping in the cave.
There, he will face Altuga.
While Osman thinks he'll get the treasure,
...he'll fall into our net, huh?
Mother Sultan.
You've started to wind around.
Not wind.
I'll storm around!
Osman will get ruined...
...and lose his leaves one by one.
Osman is running into the death clutch.
We'll wait until they are trapped, nokers.
The journey they started
for the gold will be their grave.
Osman, your poor mind...
...will let you down this time.
What if she is telling the truth?
What if they really kill my Halime tomorrow?
No...
No, I have to do something.
-Don't, mother.
We cannot trust the word of that snake Sofia.
-We don't have time.
Three days.
She says they will kill Halime if
she doesn't go there in three days.
What if it's too late tomorrow, Gonca?
Mother, Sofia is doing this to be set free.
That traitor can do anything for that.
She is playing with your pain.
Mother, we cannot trust her.
-But...
...what if Sofia is telling the truth?
What if they really kill her?
I lost my daughter once.
I experienced that grief.
I cannot resist losing her again...
...without coming together with her.
We won't lose her, mother.
We will come together with my sister.
But that snake Sofia is lying.
She couldn't have known
that she would get caught.
Mother..
Let's just wait for my father.
Come here.
My Bey.
The cave where they have
hidden the treasure is just ahead.
Now, they must have taken all kinds
of measures to protect the gold, my Bey.
Okay, okay.
Now there will be too many
nokers at the place we will go.
We will kill them all. If...
...any of them survives...
...then we will pay a heavy price. Know that.
As you order my Bey.
Come on now.
We will go to the cave
on foot. Draw your swords.
Okay.
Osman is coming Altuga.
Let him come.
Get ready to shed blood Nokers.
Our prey is approaching us.
Everyone take cover, come on!
Come on!
Did you make your decision, Bala?
You lost your daughter once. You
don't want to lose her again, right?
You will take me to my daughter, Sofia.
It's not that easy, Bala.
Why would you let me live
after taking your daughter?
I have to be sure that...
...you won't kill me.
We will get out of here
secretly. Just you and me.
If I don't have swords...
...you won't have any either.
Good.
I won't take my sword with me.
I will put it here while we are leaving.
You will take me to my daughter.
And I won't take your
dirty life and I will let you go.
This is our deal.
I will do this for my Halime, Sofia.
Come on. Get
Get up
I gave Alps duties.
We will leave before they return.
Walk!
Near Osman Bey Secret Tents
So you took refuge here, huh?
But you cannot run away from Ulugan.
I found you.
Come on!
Walk!
Walk, you snake, walk!
We have to leave before Alps return. Come on!
Come on! You will take me to my daughter!
Walk!
Come on!
Wait.
Move Sofia.
Come on.
Walk!
Come on, walk, Sofia!
From here on, we will be careful.
We will move more quietly.
Stop!
Be careful.
As you see..
...there are traps here.
Thank you Osman Bey.
Everyone should be careful where they step.
Those dogs set traps everywhere.
-Come on.
Prepare the arrows.
Alps... prepare your bows.
As you order, my Bey.
-Shoot your arrows.
Come on now.
Osman.
Osman and..
...his low companions.
What happened?
You seem shocked.
Did you really think we would just
leave our treasure to you like that?
This is...
...the end of the way for you, Altuga.
Turn back from the path you have taken.
Altuga...
As Cerkutay said...
Come on.
Ask for forgiveness when
you still have the chance.
Accept Islam.
Accept it...
...so I will forgive you.
I will never give up.
Keep your faith to yourself.
Then..
...you will die.
You cannot decide...
...who will die and who will live, Osman.
Nokers!
You left us no choice then.
-Attack!
Come on valiants! Kill them!
Even if I thought for
years, I never would have
imagined that you would
be my savior angel Bala.
You..
...you took me out of your tribe huh?
Do not test my patience, Sofia.
Just tell me which way we will go.
To my daughter. To your Halime.
She is not your..
Let me tell you again...
She is not your Halime anymore.
She is a true Christian.
And she hates Turks!
Because I raised her. -Sofia!
I will cleanse my child from your poison.
I will set you free for my daughter today.
But I swear, I will never give up on my revenge.
Walk!
Your daughter, huh?
Can I come in?
Come in.
Esenbike Hatun.
I have important news.
Tell me, I will decide
if it is important or not.
Sofia.
She is an important person for Byzantine.
She is Ulugan's and our ally.
-So? -Osman captured her.
He has our strongest ally. Give them orders...
-You insolent man!
Who are you to advise me?
And they say Kayis are smart.
Who did you take after, Ilbay?
What did I tell you when I came here?
Sorry, Esenbike Hatun.
If we save her, we can...
I don't have allies!
I have servants!
Get lost!
You've wasted my time enough!
Die, brother.
Cerkutay, now go and take your revenge.
Thank you my Bey.
Shame on the efforts I made for you, Altuga.
Don't you have a heart?
How can you do this to us?
Stop speaking, let your sword speak, brother.
I will be silent now.
But my swords will never remain silent.
How much farther do we have to go, Sofia?
Do you think I don't know that
Byzantine patrols are placed here?
But..
...we will go this way.
Soldiers don't come here.
Then..
...after we get out of the forest...
...we will arrive in a hidden
Christian village in a secret city.
Your daughter is there.
My Halime is there, huh?
Bala.
Aren't you afraid, huh?
Aren't you afraid that I will kill you when
you take your daughter and set me free?
I risked everything for my daughter, Sofia.
I made an agreement with a snake.
With you.
I saved my enemy from captivity.
Think about what I can do
for my daughter. And fear.
There is no time to wait.
I will take Sofia out of the tribe.
Only I will go with her.
She will take me to Halime.
Mother, that snake
is setting a trap.
Sure she is!
But we will set a trap against her as well.
You will take Gonca and
Alps and follow us secretly.
You don't have to be afraid, Bala.
We made an agreement. And we
will stay loyal to that agreement, right?
Come on.
Sofia.
If we don't arrive before my
soldiers, your daughter will die.
Come on!
Move.
Alaaddin.
-We should get closer. We may lose them.
Just in case, Gonca. We
shouldn't draw suspicion.
That snake can do anything.
We will keep tracking from a distance.
Alps, stand ready!
Master Sofia thanks you for hosting her.
You vile dogs.
Allah is the greatest!
Nokers, we're drawing back to the cave!
-Nokers!
-Cerkutay, are you alright?
I'm fine.
Alright
-Come here, Osman.
-Where are you going, dog?
Just wait.
Osman.
I thought your mind was working
like a wolf's mind. But I was wrong.
It was just to stall you.
What are you talking about, dastard?
Easy, fiery boy.
I'm saying... While you're after the gold here,
...Ulugan has gone to raid your secret tribe.
What?
-Dastards.
-Cerkutay.
Don't do it. Don't.
Otherwise, we'll all burn. All of us.
But today it's not me but you who will burn.
Good bye, brother.
-Alps!
My Bey.
All the tents will be repaired.
May Allah be pleased with you, Holofira Hatun.
You're taking care of us
despite all the troubles.
Don't mention it. This is my duty.
To make you feel comfortable.
Sister, I was looking for you everywhere.
You said you'd rest.
Fatma, I'm resting.
My resting is taking care of people's needs.
I'm not tiring myself, anyway.
Don't worry. I'm tiring the alps.
-Nokers are coming!
-They found our tribe!
Come on, you go!
My father and alps aren't
here. What should we do?
-We will fight. Hold the entrances, alps!
-Sisters, come on!
Hold the entrances! Fight!
-Draw back! Draw back!
-I will make Ulugan pay!
Wait! We have no time for this!
Is my precious living here?
Take me to her.
Almost there, Bala. Be patient.
Come on, Sofia. Come on.
Is she alright? Did anyone come?
No, she's been waiting for you for days.
It will be worth this.
I have a gift for her.
Move, move.
You demon.
Stop struggling in vain, Bala.
You lost.
Demon! You snake!
Where is my daughter?
What did you do to her, Sofia?
I didn't take you...
...to your daughter but your hell.
I was sure that you would fall into my trap.
I was going to take you down here...
...with a trick if something went wrong.
Right, Hristo?
We planned this before.
You're in my clutches again, Bala.
This is the end for you.
It was your trick, huh?
-I'll kill you. Where is my daughter?
-No, Bala. You played a trick too.
The difference is..
I ruined your game.
Your son and daughter-in-law...
...fell into my trap too.
If you hurt them, I will
give you such a death...
-I'll kill you, Sofia.
-You thought you'd meet Halime, huh?
You thought you'd meet Halime.
Today, you're going to lose Alaaddin too.
And you aren't going to die
before getting blind due to pain.
Alaaddin... No, my Alaaddin.
My Alaaddin.
-My Bey.
-Alps. My son.
Is everyone alright?
-I'm fine, my Bey.
-We're good, my Bey.
My Bey... My Bey...
Where is Cerkutay Bey? Has anyone seen him?
-Cerkutay! My brother!
-Cerkutay!
My Bey, there he is! Cerkutay!
My brother! Cerkutay!
Get up.
Are you alright?
I'm fine, my Bey. I'm fine.
Pull yourself together. Are you alright?
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Come on, pull yourself together.
-Pull yourself together.
-I will be alright, my Bey.
-You're good, brother.
-Let's go to the tribe, Orhan.
-Alright, my Bey.
-My Bey, you go ahead.
We will come after you.
Cerkutay and the other alps aren't very well.
We'll come after you, my Bey.
Let's go, Orhan.
Brother.
I'm the messenger of the death.
You can't run away from me.
Osman and the alps aren't here.
Stop struggling in vain,
hatun. You will just die tired!
Attack, nokers!
Sisters, come on!
They did their part.
It's just the beginning, Sargun.
Osman is going to pay the price of his decision.
What's your plan?
I'm getting Osman's alps tracked.
I took them to the Kayi
tribe to let them follow.
Nokers are watching them from behind silently.
Osman's secret tribe.
I'll tell you where it is, Ulugan.
And when it's time, you will burn it down.
And Osman will go down
on his knees to beg like a dog!
Now it's only me who can
bring peace or war in these lands.
My sword is bloodthirsty, mother.
What are we waiting for?
Let's go.
Don't worry, son.
Your mother will give you blood if
you want blood and life if you want life.
Nokers!
Draw your swords and attack!
I never lose Bala. You will learn this.
I took your daughter from
you years ago, and today...
..I killed your son.
Even the devil would be ashamed of what you did!
Sofia, I will kill you in such a way that...
Stop with these threats, Bala.
Stop!
Cry for your son.
Sofia..
Because my soldiers killed him, Bala.
Sofia
Mother! Mother, where are you?
-Mother!
Alaeddin... Alaeddin
-Mother, where are you?
-Mother! -Mother!
-Mother!
-Mother, where are you? -Mother!
Where are you? Where are you mother?
Look everywhere! Mother!
Where are you?
Alaeddin, they are doing something.
Sofia's jackals have disguised
themselves as village's folk.
Damn it Hristo!
They survived!
Come with me!
Something is happening here.
Alaeddin!
My Gonca, are you alright?
I am, are you alright?
-I am.
Are you ready?
I am always ready.
Scholar. What about you?
Sure I am.
Now let's burn this village
down and save my mother.
Come, come here.
Kill all of them!
We ruined your trap Sofia.
Now there is no way out for you.
Come.
Come. Come and see.
You will never escape from here, Bala.
Come, come Sofia!
Father...
My Allah, protect them...
Ulugan, not even death will save you from me.
Come on!
My Allah, protect them... Protect them
Come here, you infidels!
What did you to my people? To my tribe?
My people... My tribe
We couldn't arrive on time, my Bey.
We could not.
They killed our poor people.
Ulugan!
They burned it down.
If my name is Osman Bey...
...I will bury you alive!
...I will put out these flames...
...with your blood.
Ulugan...
Fatma!
Holofira!
No...
Fatma!